Abhijeet Madhavrao Khambe Java Microservices DevOps Professional

Technical Manager (16.2 Years experience)

Email: abhijeetmkhambe@gmail.com

Address: Pune, India **Phone:** +91 8788863348

Sex: Male | DOB: 31/08/1983 | Nationality: Indian

Languages: English

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/abhijeetk27

JOB SKILLS

- Accomplished Java and DevOps professional with extensive experience in backend software development in Banking domain.
- Proficient in application development using latest technologies Java 8, Java 11, Java 17,
 Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA, Micro services, Oracle Database and deployment using
 Dockerization in Openshift Container Platform and Kubernetes. Experience in Jenkins
 CICD Pipeline, SonarQube, Appdynamics, Kibana.
- Expertise of working in Agile and scrum software environment & involved in agile ceremonies from refinement, sprint planning, daily scrum and sprint review.
- Deputing responsibilities to team members by providing appropriate Solution use cases.
- Skillful in application development with OOPS, SOLID principles & Design patterns.
- Prompt and effective delivery of Tasks & User stories as per the Sprint schedule.
- 5-months international experience in Poole (United Kingdom) for post-production support.
- 5-months international experience in Pittsburgh (USA) for post-production support.

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

Frameworks	Spring, Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA, Hibernate, Rest
Languages	Java 8, Java 11, Java 17, Python, Unix, PL/SQL
Tools & Technologies	Eclipse, Oracle Database, Maven 3.0, Jenkins, Docker, Openshift, Kubernetes, JIRA, Appdynamics, Kibana, SonarQube, Checkmarx, IBM BPM
Repositories / Version Control	Bitbucket, Git, SVN

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practioner

EXPERIENCE

Mar 2019 – Present

Technical Manager

Capgemini, Pune, India

- Engaging in stories estimation in sprint planning & work on challenging user stories.
- Extensively creating complex backend (REST) API's using Java, Spring boot, JPA.
- Architected dockerisation of 14 backend and front end services of the application.
- Development of the environment based Kubernetes deployment configuration of all the microservices.
- Comprehensively delivering applications in all environments using Openshift Container platform using Kubernetes.
- Developing pipelines in Jenkins (CICD), and setting up code coverage pipeline in Sonarqube.
- Created Appdynamics configuration for all the microservices to help analyze performance of individual REST API within each and every microservice.
- Synchronizing with BA's & stakeholders, plan & propose solutions to the blockers.
- Leading team, refactoring, deployments, code reviews, interviewing and recruiting new candidates.

Achievement

Recognized by client for prompt application development, configuration and deployment
of all the microservices in the Openshift Container Platform and providing a stable
application environment with no downtime.

Nov 2011 – Mar 2019

Project Lead

BNY Mellon Technologies India Pvt Ltd, Pune, India

- Developed Corporate Trust Transition Workflow application in IBM BPM and Java as a solution to manual email based work.
- Developed Email Case Management application which aimed to configure 120 email boxes in Microsoft Outlook. A listener was designed in Java which will read the incoming emails to the mailbox every 10 seconds. If an un-read email if found, it will be read and a new case is created.
- Developed Lotus Notes Remediation application with aim to retire Lotus Notes email box with automated flow in Java based application.
- Worked in Poole (UK) and Pittsburgh (USA) during deployment of the application and providing initial support to the users post application delivery. Helped providing fix to the issues identified after initial go-live period.
- All the Java based applications were developed using Microservice based architecture.
- Managing the Build and deployment using Jenkins and BXP using Docker container.
- Effectively engaged in resolving Triage and testing cycle issues before deployment.

Achievement

 Recognized for providing prompt support to the users at onsite after post production delivery.

Jan 2008 – Oct 2011 •

Systems Engineer

Infosys Ltd., Pune, India

- Attributed in developing Reports functionality using jasper reports, Customization of Finacle banking product Integrator API's, Developing custom menu's from the existing product menu as per the requirement of the bank as well as creating new menus, Exception handling.
- Responsibility of installations and Setup for the WAS Profile, Creation of Oracle Database, applying patches and maintaining VSS for the team.
- Participated in HLD, LLD for the enhancements, debugging & testing of the module.

EDUCATION

Sep 2002- May 2007

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and

Telecommunication Engineering

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, India

LANGUAGES

- English Fluent
 - German Elementary level

PERSONAL

SKILLS

- Leadership Managed team of 20 resources.
 - Providing weekly/monthly reports to the top management as and when requested.
 - Actively participating in the hiring process and selecting best of the talent.
 - Confident, articulate, and professional speaking abilities and experience.
 - Attentive listener & speaker. Leading, & delegating abilities.